你确定他九点后才离开的吗
And you're sure he didn't leave until after 9:00?
当然  我们看了魔鬼队虐游骑兵队的比赛
Absolutely. We watched the Devils demolish the Rangers.
七点开始的
The game started at 7:00.
比赛间隙你们谁都没出去
Neither of you stepped out between periods,
捎点啤酒  买个披萨吗
get beer, pick up a pizza?
我们一直待在我家
We stayed at my place.
自始至终都在一起
We were together the whole time.
-你说魔鬼队赢了  -对  4比0
- And you said the Devils won? - Yup. 4-zip.
寇瓦恰克拿到两分  安诺特和普瑞西各得一分
Kovalchuk had two, Arnott and Parise each had one,
马蒂一分未丢
and Marty got the shutout.
你说谁  马蒂
I'm sorry. Marty?
马丁·布罗德
Martin Brodeur.
魔鬼队这二十年来的明星守门员
Devils' starting goalie for, like, the past 20 years.
他的发挥一如既往的好
He played awesome as usual.
法官阁下  我请求援引
Your honor, may I submit the sports page
2011年10月9日新泽西日报体育版
from The New Jersey Chronicle On October 9th, 2011.
反对  与本案无关
Objection. Relevance.
为确认证人所言是否可信
Goes to the witness's credibility.
那就快点
Go quickly.
请你朗读图片下面的说明
Would you please read the caption under the photo?
"马丁·布罗德实现职业生涯
"Martin Brodeur stops 1
第36次救球  魔鬼队零封对手"
of his 36 saves on the way to a shutout victory."
如我所说
That's what I just said.
被告不可能实施抢劫
That the defendant couldn't have possibly committed the robbery
因为他和你在一起
because he was with you
看门神马丁·布罗德大展身手
watching Martin Brodeur shut out the Rangers.
对
Yes.
非常感谢
Thank you.
法官阁下  我请求援引10月10日
Your honor, may I submit the chronicle sports page
新泽西日报体育版
from October 10th?
法官阁下
Your honor.
你是这么理解"快"的吗
This is what you call going quickly?
再两个问题  我保证
Just two more questions. I promise.
请朗读下方勾画出的部分
Please read the highlighted text at the bottom of the page.
"周日的体育版中
"In sunday's sports section,
新泽西魔鬼队守门员约翰·赫德伯格被..."
new Jersey Devils goaltender Johan Hedberg was..."
就是那个  继续
That's it. Keep going.
"误认为是马丁·布罗德
"misidentified as Martin Brodeur
图片说明及技术统计均出错"
in a photo caption and box score."
情有可原的错误
An understandable mistake.
毕竟原计划是马丁·布罗德上场
Given that Martin Brodeur was scheduled to start
结果告吹
but bowed out
因为热身时喉部被球击中
after taking a shot to the throat in warm-up.
这就说到与本案最为相关的问题
Which brings me to my most relevant question.
10月8日晚你是否和被告在一起
Did you and the defendant spend the evening of October 8th
看魔鬼队比赛
watching the Devils game on tv,
还是你不过是在日报上读到相关信息
or did you just read about the game in the chronicle
进而作伪证
while concocting this false alibi?
我  我
I... I, um...
请原谅  法官阁下
Excuse me, your honor,
我请求上前议事
may I approach?
你确定
You sure you don't want to wait
不等他说完吗
till after he answers your question?
是的
No.
我申请延期审理
I'm gonna need a continuance.
现在
Now?
你再问一个问题  辩方就会一败涂地
You're one answer away from destroying their whole defense.
-拜托  -闭嘴
- Come on. - Oh, shut up.
你心里清楚
You know it's true.
-我们把这了结了吧  -我做不到
- Let's finish this up. - I can't.
为什么不行
Why the hell not?
因为我感觉我心脏病发了
Because I think I'm having a heart attack.
好吧  快叫救护车
Great. Call an ambulance.
总监：
zlean
以为自己心脏病发  其实不然
Thinks he had a heart attack but didn't.
他的心电图  心肌酶谱和心脏导管介入检查
His EKG, cardiac enzymes, and catheterization
都显示正常
are all normal.
因为那是焦虑发作
'Cause it's an anxiety attack.
估计是因为他人到四十
Probably because he just turned 40
仍然叫做汤米
and still goes by the name "Tommy".
不是焦虑
It's not anxiety.
急症室医生询问过他的妻子
The E.R. docs interviewed his wife.
证实他状态一直不错
She confirmed he's been feeling fine.
工作和家庭都没有异常情况
Nothing out of the ordinary at work or at home.
她大概也以为她老公
Probably also believes that he thinks
嫌萨尔玛·海耶克的胸太大
Salma Hayek's breasts are too big.
所以我坚持让他住院
Which is why I had them admit him anyway
并用阿普唑仑[抗焦虑药]治疗
and treat with Alprazolam.
没效果
No improvements.
-因为  -因为对某些病人来说
- Because... - Because for some patients
被诊断为焦虑性障碍
the diagnosis of anxiety disorder
反而会加剧焦虑
can actually increase anxiety,
所以我才会告诉他
which is also why I told him
他有轻度呼吸道感染
he had a minor respiratory infection
通过药物治疗  可以很容易痊愈
that was easily curable by the medication.
你说谎了
You lied?
我排除了心脏病和焦虑性障碍
I ruled out heart attack and anxiety disorder.
有意思
Interesting.
我知道
I know.
真厉害
Impressive.
你是指他耍小伎俩
What, the wiliness
排除了焦虑吗
with which Foreman ruled out anxiety
还是他遇到我之前的完全不知变通
or his complete wiliness-less-ness before he met me?
是你居然能把果酱抹得每页都是
The fact that you managed to smear jelly on nearly every page.
带状疱疹导致的胸痛可能在皮疹之前出现
Shingles could cause chest pain before a rash appeared.
疼痛会局限在一个皮肤节段
Pain would be restricted to one dermatome.
不会超出的
It wouldn't cross them.
如果是哮喘导致的气胸就有可能
Asthma-induced pneumothorax would
且可能不会在后前位胸片上显示
and might not show up on a posteroanterior X-ray.
没有哮喘病史
No history of asthma.
还做了胸部侧位片
They did a lateral view as well.
没有气胸的迹象
No sign of a pneumothorax
也没有深沟征
or deep sulcus sign.
我曾治疗过一个有类似症状的囚犯
I treated an inmate once with similar symptoms
他试图用氯气毒死自己的牢友
after he tried to poison his cellmate with chlorine gas.
他没意识到牢房空气共享吗
He didn't realize sharing a cell also meant sharing the air?
氯气集中在近地面
Chlorine gas pools near the ground
他以为自己在上铺就没事
he thought he'd be safe in the top bunk.
为什么会有人对我们的患者下毒
Well, why would anyone try to poison our guy?
他就靠把别人送进监狱谋生
He makes a living sending people to prison.
但他不在狱内  再说他又没被
But he's not in prison, and it's kind of hard
关在密闭室内  怎么用毒气毒他啊
to gas a guy unless you can seal him in a room first.
所以阿尔宙斯才创造了一个物质有三态的世界
Which is why Arceus created a universe with 3 states of matter
和300种能引发他症状的固态液态毒物
and 300 solid or liquid poisons that could cause his symptoms.
阿尔宙斯
Arceus?
去查查吧  并碱化他的尿液
Look it up. And alkalinize his urine.
去他家搜寻一下  和他老婆谈谈
Go search his home, talk to his wife,
看看能不能套出她用的什么毒
see if you can get her to tell us what she used.
等等  你为什么认为是他妻子下的毒
Wait, why would you think his wife poisoned him?
因为最危险的  不是外贼
Because dangerous people don't break into your home,
而是家贼
they live in it.
虽然他的孩子已经到了希望爸爸去死的年纪
And although his kids are old enough to want daddy dead,
要说真动手却还嫩了点
they're still too young to do anything about it.
你脑袋里的世界一定和谐美满
Must be such a pleasure to live in your head.
你说得对
You're right.
孩子可能早熟
Kids might be precocious.
你去搜查他家
You handle his house.
你去应付他和他老婆
You handle him and his wife.
他们可以出去溜达  什么都不做吗
They get to just hang out and do nothing?
需要帮忙的话  随便挑
If you need help, you can take whoever you want.
-我选陶博  -我选陶博
- I'll take Taub. - I'll take Taub.
-有意思  -不  这没什么
- Interesting. - No, it's not.
非此即彼
It was a 50/50 choice.
陶博还是朴克我都无所谓
I'm totally fine with Taub or Park.
正好  我选陶博
Cool. I'll take Taub.
那我选朴克
And I'll take Park.
真好玩
That was fun.
一点也不
Not really.
干得好  头儿
Nice move, boss.
对患者撒谎
Lying to the patient.
我别无选择
I had no choice.
我知道豪斯不会接这病例
I knew House wouldn't take the case
除非我先排除焦虑
unless I ruled out anxiety.
你需要个女朋友
You need a girlfriend.
好管住我  不对病人撒谎吗
To keep me from lying to patients?
好给你你所需的刺激
To give you the excitement you need
那样你就不用去找刺激了
so you don't go looking for it.
你已经不在豪斯手底下干活了
You're not working for House anymore,
也就是说如果你犯事
which means you no longer have him
也不能把责任推给他
to blame if you get caught.
我不是在找刺激
I'm not looking for excitement.
我是在干我的本职工作
I'm doing my job,
其中就包括让豪斯做好他的本职工作
part of which is to make sure House does his.
找个女朋友这主意不错
Girlfriend might not be so bad.
这比你要做的事风险小多了
It's less dangerous than where you're headed.
这话是从我这个要付一份赡养费
And that's from a guy with one alimony
还要养两个孩子的人口中说出的
and two child support payments.
这个新的弯道控制装置
It's this new curve control thing.
当它感应到我入弯速度太快时
It automatically slows the car when it senses
能自动减慢车速
I'm taking a curve too fast.
你真的以为我很在乎你的车吗
You really think I care about your car,
或是你在想方设法不谈及
or are you just trying to avoid talking
你为什么不喜欢和我一起工作
about why you don't like working with me?
这没什么可说的
There's nothing to talk about.
豪斯小时候就喜欢
House liked poking ant hills
拿着木棍捅蚁冢
with a stick when he was a kid,
他现在是对我们故技重施
and now he wants to do the same with us.
豪斯是个混蛋  但他直觉很准
House is an ass, but he's an intuitive ass.
显然他看出些问题了
He obviously noticed something.
对  那就是我们合作得很愉快
Yeah, the fact that we work well together.
他喜欢坐山观虎斗  就想找人虐一下
He thrives on conflict and is looking for someone to torment.
可别落入他的圈套
Don't let it be us.
我觉得那不可能
I don't see how that's possible.
汤米在办公室里很受欢迎
Tommy's the most popular guy in his office.
甚至有被告被判刑后还感谢他
He's even had defendants thank him after they were sentenced.
他们为什么感谢他
Why would they thank him?
因为他不把他们当成人渣来看
Because he doesn't treat them like scum.
他让他们感觉他是在帮助他们
He makes them feel like he's helping
替他们提出恳求或是
by offering a plea or even just
让他们在监狱中赎罪  以安抚良心
by letting them pay their debt and clear their conscience.
就算有人想下毒
And even if someone wanted to poison him,
我看他们也没有机会啊
I don't see how they would do it.
他只吃喝家里做的东西
He never eats or drinks anything that we haven't made at home.
等等  你没夸张吗
Wait. You mean literally,
比如  在外面连一瓶水都不喝吗
like, not even a bottle of water?
不喝
No.
那么他显然是在害怕什么
So he was obviously afraid of something.
对  怕耗子  老鼠和蟑螂
Yeah, rats, mice, cockroaches.
我从法律学院毕业后
My first job out of law school
第一份工作是在卫生部
was at the health department.
如果你也见过我见过的一些厨房
If you'd have seen some of the kitchens
或是食品处理厂
or the processing plants I have,
你也会只吃自己做的东西
you'd cook all your own food too.
毒物不一定在食物里
Poison wouldn't have to be in food.
你最近有没有收到
Have you gotten any
什么陌生的信件或是包裹
strange letters or packages recently?
没有
No.
也不一定是在工作的地方中毒
You also wouldn't have to be at work.
我们有两个小孩
We've got two young kids.
我在家里绝对不可能
There's definitely no poisons
意外接触到有毒物质
I could have accidentally been exposed to at home.
如果不是意外呢
What if it wasn't an accident?
你和你妻子关系怎么样
How are things between you and your wife?
你是在问  我是否
Are you asking me if I think
认为我妻子想杀我吗
my wife is trying to kill me?
对
Yes, I am.
绝对不可能
Absolutely not.
我这人可是时刻警惕着
This is coming from a man whose eyes are wide open.
我起诉过几百个犯下卑劣罪行的丈夫  妻子
I have prosecuted hundreds of despicable acts by husbands, wives,
还有父母
parents.
我敢保证...
I can assure you...
我爱我的丈夫
I love my husband,
而且我绝对不会
and I would not ever even for a second
有去伤害他的想法
consider doing anything to hurt him.
车库里没有
No pesticides,
杀虫剂  化肥或是燃料
fertilizers, or fuel in the garage.
你有什么发现吗
You find anything?
没有  我在这里甚至
No, there's not even a bottle
连一瓶清洁剂都没有找到
of wite-out in this place.
也许我们应该再找找
Maybe we should look again.
也许我们应该在警察赶到前就撤
Maybe we should leave before the police get here.
就算有人看到我们闯进来 然后报警
Well, even if a neighbor saw us break in and called 911,
除非说我们携带武器  否则就不是首要案件
unless they said we were armed, it's low priority.
所以我们应该还有五分钟
We've got another five minutes.
他是一名检查官
He's a prosecutor.
他显然认识很多警察
Obviously he knows a lot of cops.
他的房子才不会不是首要案件呢
His house is not gonna be low priority.
有道理
Good point.
等等
Wait.
餐厅是在墙那边
The dining room's on the other side of that wall.
对  怎么了
Yeah, so?
但是它似乎在这边多出了三英尺
But it ends, like, three feet further over.
你是在开玩笑吧
You've got to be kidding me.
你刚刚还想赶紧逃出去
A second ago, you wanted to run like hell,
现在却想在这儿找密道吗
and now you want to look for secret passages?
在冰箱上有一块磁铁
There's a magnet on the fridge
是用来打开有童锁的柜子的
they use to open child-proofed cabinets.
去拿过来
Go get it.
快点
Hurry up.
给
Here.
天啊
Holy crap.
先别说
Don't tell me.
我猜是吃醋的妻子在厨房里
The jealous wife in the dining room
手里拿着联吡啶除草剂
with bipyridyl herbicide.
我们没找到任何有毒物质
We didn't find any poisons.
但你们显然找到些东西
Well, you obviously found something.
对
Yeah.
一个隐蔽的掩体
A hidden bunker
里面的枪足以守卫诺克斯堡
with enough guns to defend Fort Knox.
诺克斯堡是美国陆军装甲中心
美国陆军装甲学校等机构均所在地
或是攻进去
Or break into it.
太帅了
Cool.
不可能  你们肯定闯错家了
That's impossible. You must have broken into the wrong house.
那么你的邻居就很诡异了
Then you have creepy neighbors,
因为房子里到处是你们和孩子的照片
because there were photos of you and your kids all over.
我不明白
I don't understand.
这怎么可能...
How could this...
那是去年装修时我建的密室
I had it put in during the remodel last year.
但我们是一起商量装修计划的啊
But we went over the plans together.
它没在计划里
It's not in the plans.
我不想让市里知道
I didn't want the city to know about it.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我应该告诉你的
I should have told you.
只是...
I just...
我不想你和孩子们担心
I didn't want you and the kids to worry.
担心什么啊
About what?
汤米  是什么事啊
Tommy, what is it?
你为什么认为你需要这么多枪啊
Why would you think you needed so many guns?
你不会相信的
You're not gonna believe this.
国将不国  天下大乱
Imperio absenti chaos regit.
他担心"大而不倒"只适用于银行
He's worried that "too big to fail" applies to our banks
而不适用于我们的政府
but not our government.
你怎么知道的
How'd you know?
因为每个建造掩体
Because that's what every idiot
并装满冲锋枪的傻瓜都怕那个
with a bunker full of assault rifles is scared of.
希瑟·斯威尼在吗
Heather Sweeney.
请再等几分钟
Uh, it'll just be a couple of minutes
就会有人来给你看病了
till someone's ready to see you.
也许那不是犯傻  而是一个症状
Maybe it's not stupidity. It's a symptom.
滥用可卡因可以引起妄想症和胸痛
Cocaine abuse can cause paranoia and chest pain.
这不一定就是妄想症
This isn't necessarily paranoia.
社会确实是会崩溃的
Societies do fall apart.
看看伦敦还有那些暴动
Look what happened with London and the riots.
个别地区的暴动和整个文明的陷落
There's a difference between an isolated riot
是有区别的
and the fall of civilization.
艾普尔·唐纳森在吗
April Donaldson.
抱歉  叫错名字了
Sorry. Misspoke.
想象一下如果有恐怖分子
Imagine what would happen if there was
破坏咱们的食物供给链
a terrorist attack on the food supply
或是散布传染病  造成抗生素限量供给会怎么样
or a pandemic where we had to ration antibiotics.
这太荒谬了
That's ridiculous.
犀利啊
Ouch.
你闭嘴吧
Oh, shut up.
我们知道你想干什么  你不会得逞的
We know what you're trying to do, and it's not gonna work.
你的话确实挺重的
It was a little harsh.
-别那么...  -什么  妄想狂吗
- Stop being so... - What? Paranoid?
如果你猜错了  你可就出洋相了
You're gonna look pretty foolish if that was the wrong guess.
我认为你是个好人  一名优秀的医生
I think you're a good person and a fine doctor,
但是如果你认为所有人都需要一个
but it's ridiculous to think anyone needs
军火库的话  你就太荒谬了
an arsenal of assault weapons.
他显然有妄想症  会不会是法尔氏病
He's obviously paranoid. What about Fahr's disease?
-他没有产生幻觉  -那是我们还没发现
- He's not hallucinating. - As far as we know.
我们应该做一个精神状态检查
We should do a mental status examination
给他的基底神经节做个CT
And get a CT of his basel ganglia.
不对  不该这么做
No, we shouldn't.
如果不是中毒了  最有可能是心房纤颤
If it's not poison, it's most likely atrial fibrillation
由甲状腺机能亢进
brought on by hyperthyroidism
或睡眠呼吸暂停综合症引发
or sleep apnea.
看来有小妞吵架可围观了
Looks like we got ourselves a good, old-fashioned cat fight.
我们没有吵架
No, we don't.
我们只是意见不合
We have a reasoned disagreement.
好吧  只有一个办法能解决争议
Still there's only one way to settle this.
实际是有两个办法
Actually there's two,
但是第一种  我们果冻不够
But we don't have enough jell-o for the first.
做个简单的精神状态检查
Mini-mental,
CT以及毛发取样
CT, and get a hair sample
查查他有没有吸食过可卡因
to check for past cocaine use.
检查下他的甲状腺水平  再做个睡眠监测
Check his TSH levels and get a sleep study.
抱歉  为了让她俩公平对决
Sorry, we got to make it a fair fight,
你和她凑合一下吧
which means you're stuck with her.
什么叫凑合啊
He's not "stuck" with me.
而且也不是对决
And it's not a fight.
小姐抱歉
Uh, excuse me, miss.
你叫什么名字
What is your name?
梅丽尔·威尔克森
Mariel Wilkerson.
你看着不像是叫梅丽尔的嘛
You don't look like a Mariel.
轮到你了
You're up.
你怎么看  是病人有妄想症还是我有
So what do you think? Is the patient paranoid or am I?
我不认为储存武器
I don't think stockpiling weapons
是理智的表现
is the most reasoned response.
但是  见识过布卢明代尔百货公司
But, given what I've seen at Bloomingdale's
的黑色周五抢购潮[万圣节后的第一天]
on Black Friday,
我觉得他这么做也不能算是脑子有病
I wouldn't say it rises to the level of mental illness.
那我呢
And me?
同样的  见识过那抢购的场景...
Again, given what I've seen at bloomingdale's...
别让豪斯影响你
Don't let House get to you.
是你们所有人
It's all of you.
我感觉你们不尊重我
I feel like you don't respect me.
奇斯就表现得很明显
Chase certainly doesn't try to hide it.
他是尊敬你的  只是他觉得
Chase respects you. He's just more comfortable
和我搭档比较顺  因为我们认识得比较早
working with me because he's known me longer.
我不是因为你有枪才这么说的
And I'm not just saying that because you own a gun.
我没有枪
I don't own a gun.
我倒是考虑过  但是我很可能会
I've thought about it, but I'd probably end up shooting
射伤家人  比如在看到我弟弟
someone in my own family, like when my brother
往沙发后面扔指甲屑的时候
tosses his toenail clippings behind the couch.
你呢
What about you?
如果政权真被推翻
If anarchy breaks out,
我打算做我的祖先们
I plan to do what my ancestors have done
做了几个世纪的事情  逃跑
throughout the ages: run.
这计划不错啊
Sounds like a good plan.
你有空吗
You got a moment?
你别再和护士们说我要找女朋友了
Stop telling the nurses I'm looking for a girlfriend.
你怎么会觉得...
What makes you--
从早上到现在  已经有两个人邀请我吃饭
Two lunch offers and a box of cupcakes
还有人送了我一盒蛋糕
since this morning.
这么说  有几个人向你示好
So a few people are nice to you,
你首先想到的是"这真奇了怪了"
and your first thought is, "Hmm, this seems strange"?
我连自己吃午饭的时间都没有
I haven't even had enough time to eat my own lunch,
更别说四处去帮你物色女朋友了
much less run around trying to recruit nurses for yours.
我能回去工作了吗
So can I get back to work?
你骗他的  是不是
You're lying, aren't you?
我是为了他好
It's for his own good.
他没有妄想症  他就是蠢
He's not paranoid. He's just stupid.
好吧  你不是也属于这类人吗
Well, shouldn't you put yourself in that group?
你有把枪的
You own a gun.
这病人有的不是一把枪  而是个军火库
Our patient doesn't own a gun. He owns an arsenal.
而且  我没有枪
And I don't own a gun.
你有的
Yes, you do.
你是重罪犯  持枪会被送回监狱的
And you're a felon, so you'll end up back in jail.
这还真不是我没枪的N条理由中的一条
That is actually not one of the many reasons that I don't own a gun.
我要枪有什么用呢
Why would I need a gun?
唯一值得我保护的
The only thing I own worth protecting
毛贼还得拿根拐杖才能弄出我的公寓
a thief would need a crane to get out of my apartment.
你不会去买你需要的东西
You don't own anything you need.
而是买你想要的东西
You own things you want.
而你绝对是那种想要搞把枪的人
And you're definitely the type who'd want a gun.
凡是危险的东西你都喜欢
You like anything dangerous,
巨型卡车  摩托车  烟火什么的
monster trucks, motorcycles, fireworks.
人人都爱烟火
Everyone loves fireworks.
喜欢看烟火  而不是制作烟火
Watching them, not making them.
我说的是实话
I'm telling the truth.
那我纠正我的说法
I stand corrected.
如果你相信我  这事儿就此打住
If you believe me, then this issue will be resolved
别再节外生枝了
with no further action necessary.
当然
Absolutely.
这事儿还没结束  是吧
It's not resolved, is it?
离结束还早着呢
Not even close.
他没吸可卡因
It's not cocaine.
毛发取样没问题
Hair samples were clean.
看着也不像是法尔氏病
It's not looking good for Fahr's either.
没有钙化迹象
I'm not seeing any calcifications.
你肯定吗
You sure?
在未满五十岁的病人身上会难以察觉
They can be pretty hard to detect in people under 50.
-瞧见没  -什么
- See? - What?
意见不合是常有的事
We all disagree all the time.
不只是我和朴克会这样
It's not just me and Park.
挺会说话的嘛
Nice try,
不过我可不想趟你们的浑水
but I'm not getting in the middle.
那你早上为什么不愿和她一组
So why didn't you want to go with her this morning?
她人挺怪的
She's weird.
她不怪  她是个优秀的医生
She's not weird. She's a good doctor.
大部分优秀的医生都挺古怪的
Most good doctors are weird.
你看豪斯
Look at House.
我算怪吗
Am I weird?
是的  不过你长得靓  比较好忍受
Yeah, but you're hot, so it's easier to put up with.
你完全正常
You're completely normal
和你相处很愉快
and a pleasure to deal with.
你真奇怪
You're weird.
怪得很有型是吧
In a good way?
我们还是专心看病吧
Maybe we should just concentrate on the medicine.
你有枪吗
You own any guns?
你又跑题了
That's not medicine.
这话题和医学多少有点关系
But it's related to medicine. Kind of.
那你觉得呢
What do you think?
你有枪  不过不是为了自卫
Yeah, but not for protection.
尽管媒体大肆宣传社会动荡
Despite what the media would have us believe,
你还是觉得这世界很安全
you think we live in a very safe world.
你就是觉得枪支很好玩
You just think they're fun.
你怎么知道的
How did you know?
你在监狱工作
Working in prison,
知道罪犯很少随机攻击路人甲
you learned criminals rarely target random strangers,
而且你的钱多得都不知道怎么花
And you've got more money than you know what to do with,
所以你会去尝试那些看起来新鲜好玩的事物
so anything that seems different and fun's worth trying.
你呢
And you?
我在美国这边没有枪
Not here in the States.
在我老家  我有几把打袋鼠的枪
Back home, I keep a few for hunting 'roos.
你猎袋鼠的
You hunt kangaroos?
它们那么可爱
But they're so cute.
还很可口
They're also delicious.
你骗我的吧
You're screwing with me.
当然
Totally.
没有钙化
There's no calcification.
看来我们都错了
Looks like we're both wrong.
你不需要陪在这里
You don't need to stay.
要明天早上才会出结果
We won't have the results until the morning.
没关系的  我陪着他
It's okay. I'll stay.
回去吧
Go.
你也该让你妈歇歇了
I'm sure your mother's ready for a break by now, huh?
替我吻吻孩子们
Give the kids a kiss for me.
你认为世界末日来了  但却要孩子
You think it's the end of the world, but you wanted kids.
亲爱的  别这样
Oh, honey, come on.
我没认为末日将至
I don't think the world's coming to an end.
听着
Look...
你的车上有个备胎  对吧
You have a spare tire in your car, right?
那些枪就和备胎一样
That's what those guns are.
我祈求上帝不要让我用到它们
I mean, I hope to god I never have to use one.
但是如果一觉醒来
But if we can wake up
发现整个银行系统一夜间全倒闭了
and learn that the entire bank system has gone bankrupt overnight,
到时毫无准备就傻眼了
it just seems stupid not to have a jack in the trunk.
只是以防万一
Just in case.
你一直...
And you've always...
这血哪里来的
What's that from?
不知道
I don't know.
你不觉得疼吗
You don't feel that?
不觉得
No.
他整夜发高烧
He also spiked a fever overnight.
可能是肺结核
It could be TB.
你有话要说是吧
You want to say it.
-说什么  -胸片中没有肺不张
- Say what? - There's no sign of atelectasis
或肺部浸润的现象
or infiltrates on the chest x-ray.
没错  这是"她是白痴"的医学表述
Yeah. It's med-speak for she's an idiot.
系统性硬化病会导致下肢溃疡
Systemic sclerosis can cause lower extremity ulcers.
那他的症状早该出现了
It would have to be pretty far along
而他的第一个症状是几天前才出现的
because the first symptom was just a few days ago.
他的妄想症一年前就开始了
His paranoia started at least a year ago.
如果他有妄想症的话
If he's paranoid.
这么说要么就不是硬化症
So it's either not sclerosis
要么就是发展极快的硬化症
or it's extremely aggressive sclerosis.
我们应该进行皮肤活检并开始给他用依诺肝素
We should biopsy the skin lesion and start him on enoxaparin.
我们不该等活检结果出来后
Shouldn't we wait for the biopsy results
再开始治疗吗
before we start treatment?
该你表态了
Now's your chance.
她可是豁出去了
She's leading with her chin.
我同意她的看法
I agree with her.
不  你不同意
No, you don't.
这意味着你俩都是白痴
Which means you're both idiots.
干活去吧
Get to work.
我知道你不认为我是白痴
I know you don't think I'm an idiot.
有什么关系吗
Does it matter?
如果你只是拿我找乐  那没所谓
If you're just looking to amuse yourself at my expense, then no.
但如果你觉得需要耍手段
But if you feel the need to manipulate me
让我觉得自己有用  那关系大了
to make me feel useful, then yes.
我以为我们已经过了那个阶段了
I thought we'd gotten past that.
如果真过了  你就不会在这纠结了
If we hadn't gotten past that, you wouldn't be here.
但有能力并非就够了
But ability isn't always enough.
看看英格威·马尔莫斯汀就知道了
Just ask Yngwie Malmsteen.
那你是想帮我吗
So this is you trying to help me?
不  我是在帮我自己
No, this is me helping me.
同时拿你找乐
And amusing myself at your expense.
这就又回到  你为什么在乎这事呢
Which brings us back to, why do you care?
我应该得到尊重
I deserve respect.
我是个好医生
I'm a good doctor.
大家尊重你  他们只是不喜欢你而已
People respect you. They just don't like you.
你妻子呢
Where's your wife?
她需要点时间想想
She just needed some time.
看来是对枪不感冒了
Not a fan of guns I take it.
不只是枪的问题  只是...
It's not the guns. It's...
我不该对她撒谎
I shouldn't have lied about it.
我猜两者都有点
I'm guessing it's a little of both.
还有点"我怎么不认识这人"的感觉
And a little of, "Who the hell is this guy?"
我不是疯子
I'm not a nutcase.
我只是想竭尽所能
I just want to do everything I can
保护我的家庭
to protect my family.
别担心  我相信她能理解
Don't worry. I'm sure she understands.
一开始我以为是冻伤
At first, I thought it might be frostbite,
但我从没在冷的地方待过
but I haven't really been out in the cold.
但你的第一感觉还是冻伤吗
And yet your first thought was frostbite?
是的  估计我只是从外表判断的
Yeah, I guess I was just going by how it looks.
这看上去完全不像冻伤
It looks absolutely nothing like frostbite.
真的吗
You serious?
不太确定
With some difficulty.
那究竟是什么
Then what is it?
是你需要放个长假的标志
A sign that you need to take a long vacation.
至少一个月
At least a month.
休假
A vacation?
等等  是像遗愿清单那样的吗
Wait, is this like a bucket list thing?
电影《遗愿清单》
讲述两个同患癌症一贫一富的病友结伴完成未尽的心愿
是癌症
It's cancer.
是银
It's silver.
我猜可能是你老板将硝酸银与凡士林混合
I'm guessing silver nitrate mixed with petroleum jelly
涂抹在钱上
that your boss put on the petty cash
这样他就能抓住偷钱的人了
so he'd know who to have arrested for stealing it.
我去
Damn.
是啊  我去
Yeah, damn.
它会渗透进你的皮肤
It's diffused into your skin,
而唯一去除的方法
and the only way to get rid of it
就是长出新的皮肤
Is to get new skin.
一般来讲需要30天
That normally happens every 30 days.
我听说威斯康辛州的拉克罗斯
So I hear that La Crosse, Wisconsin has got
有世界上最大的啤酒罐
the world's largest beer can.
这是每天的日程
Here's the per diem schedules.
这些应该录入电脑的
These are supposed to be in the computer files.
对不起  自从克劳汀走了
Sorry. Since Claudine left,
就没人把这些数字进行录入了
no one's been inputting the numbers.
我真想克劳汀
I miss Claudine.
她是因为你才走的
She left because of you.
我以为那是娜汀
I thought that was Nadine.
-她也是  -你去哪
- Her too. - Where are you going?
你还有一个小时门诊时间呢
You still have an hour left.
优先处理急诊寻呼
Emergency page takes precedence.
-你能...  -我不知道那程序怎么用
- Can you-- - I don't know how to use the program.
那就去找会用的人
Then find someone who does.
我得走了
I got to get out of here.
收到你的寻呼了
Got your page.
你个混蛋
You're an ass.
承认吧
Admit it.
放我下来
Let me down.
你承认了就放
After you admit it.
要知道  我有点累了
You know, I'm a little tired.
-我想我要去...-好吧  我承认
- I think I'm gonna-- - All right, I admit it.
尽管我知道这里有把枪
Despite the fact that I know there's a gun in here,
但我永远找不到  因为你更狡猾
I'd never find it because you are more devious--
-聪明  -狡猾
- Clever. -Devious.
好吧好吧  聪明
All right, fine, clever.
你更聪明而且总能魔高一丈
More clever and you'll always be one step ahead of me.
你要么在备战拳击赛
You're either preparing to fight pacquiao
要么就是今天过得很不顺
or you're having one heck of a bad day.
-我叫安妮塔  -艾瑞克
- I'm Aniita. - Eric.
很高兴见到你
Nice to meet you.
你可以告诉陶博
And you can tell Taub
如果再不停止这种愚蠢的行为
that he's gonna get the same treatment
就将和这个沙包同样下场
as this heavy bag if he doesn't cut this crap out.
谁是陶博
Who's Taub?
我知道你是个好人
You know, I'm sure you're a nice person
你也不知道你被搅进什么浑水里
and you have no idea what you've gotten sucked into,
但是  说真的  我没兴趣
but, really, I'm not interested.
好吧  我肯定你是个好人
Okay, and I'm sure you're a nice person,
不过我刚从亚特兰大搬来
but I just moved from Atlanta,
这是我第一次来这个健身房
and it's my first time at this gym,
我肯定不知道这个陶博是谁
so definitely don't know who this Taub guy is,
但我完全同意  他是个混蛋
but I already agree. He's a jerk.
你确定不想重新来过吗
Are you sure you don't want to start over?
慢慢想
Take your time.
我就在附近
I'll be around.
陶博  我是福曼
Taub, it's Foreman.
我现在没空聊  有点忙
Hey, can't talk now. Little busy.
怎么回事
What's going on?
这需要氟哌利多
Need some droperidol in here!
我得挂了
I gotta go!
他产生了幻觉以为自己被熊袭击了
He was hallucinating he was being attacked by bears.
再次表明是妄想症
Points again to paranoia.
我同意
I agree.
不过并非是再次
Except for the "Again".
急性发作更可能是土拉菌病
Acute onset points to tularemia.
或者是慢性的  那就是自身免疫疾病
Or it's been chronic, which points to gad autoimmunity.
可以解释神经功能缺损
Explains the neurological impairment
以及正常的血检结果
as well as the normal blood work.
土拉菌病也不一定会在血检中查到
Tularemia doesn't always show up in blood work either.
你们知道还有什么在血检中也查不到吗
You know what else doesn't show up in the blood work?
就是没病
Nothing.
可能是精神病
This could be all psychiatric.
未经治疗的精神分裂症
An untreated schizoid disorder
他终于无法抑制了
he's finally lost the ability to suppress.
精神分裂症不会引起皮肤溃疡或高烧
Schizophrenia doesn't cause skin ulcers or fevers.
没错  但因妄想而用脏指甲抠皮肤
No, but digging delusions out of your skin
就可能导致这两种症状
with dirty fingernails could cause both.
我不认为这是精神病例
I don't think he's a psych case.
因为你对妄想症产生了妄想
Because you're paranoid about paranoia.
因为他的症状表明是感染
Because his symptoms point towards an infection
并已经扩散到脑部
that spread to his brain.
我认为我们应该用大剂量的广谱...
I think we should treat with high-dose, broad-spectrum--
如果是自身免疫疾病那会杀了他的
Which will kill him if it's a gad autoimmunity.
按自身免疫疾病治疗
Treat for gad.
用皮质激素并静脉滴注免疫球蛋白
Corticosteroids and IV immunoglobulin.
我不是妄想
I'm not paranoid.
他们也不是不喜欢我
And they don't dislike me.
他们甚至都不了解我
They don't even really know me.
谁告诉你的
They tell you that?
我没问  因为你不会相信他们的回答
I didn't ask because you wouldn't believe the answer.
如果这么想你能好过点  就随你吧
If it makes you feel better to think that.
大家都不喜欢的是你
You're the one everyone dislikes.
估计你都不觉得是自身免疫疾病
You probably don't even think it's gad.
你同意她只是因为你认为
You're just agreeing with her because you think
这会引起我们之间更多的纷争
it'll create more conflict between us.
想得到答案只有一个方法
There's only one way to find out.
实际上  有两个方法
Actually, there's two.
我们还在等果冻送来
We're still waiting for that Jell-O delivery.
记得把进展汇报给我
Let me know how it goes.
抓住你啦
Gotcha!
你这个可怜的傻缺
You poor dumb bastard.
干得好
Touche.
天啊  我正是我需要的
God, this is exactly what I needed.
无比赞同
Tell me about it.
安妮塔
Anita.
-天啊  -那是谁  你室友吗
- Oh, my god. - Who is that, your roommate?
你必须得走了
It's just you have to go.
等等  到底怎么了
Wait a minute, what's the big deal?
快走吧  我以后再解释
Please. I'll explain later.
请赶紧走吧  拜托了
Just hurry up. Please.
你有男友了吗
You have a boyfriend?
不  他不是我男友
No, he's not my boyfriend.
他是我丈夫
He's my husband.
真的很抱歉
I'm really sorry.
我以为你明天才回来呢
Hey! I thought you weren't getting back till tomorrow.
他烧得非常厉害
His fever's going through the roof,
也就证明不是自身免疫疾病
which means we were wrong about gad
而且激素使得感染急剧恶化了
and the steroids kicked the infection into high gear.
也可能就是自身免疫疾病  不过治晚了
Or it's gad, and we started treatment too late.
-加大激素的量  -不能这么做
- Increase the steroid dose. - We can't.
如果确实是感染  我们无疑会害死他
If it's an infection, we'll kill him for sure.
神经系统症状恶化得这么快
With neurological symptoms progressing this fast,
他怎样都会死
he's dead either way.
如果我们增大激素的量
If we increase the steroids,
而他能多活几天
then either death comes slower,
就表示是自身免疫疾病而我们治得太晚
which means we were too late with the gad,
如果加速了死亡
or death comes faster,
则说明确实是感染  我们犯傻了
which means we were too stupid with the infection.
我们没按感染治已经很傻了
We were already stupid with the infection,
但还不算太晚
but it's not too late.
他还年轻  两天前还非常健康
He's young, and he was perfectly healthy two days ago.
如果给他个机会  他能挺过去的
He can fight this off if we give him a chance.
好吧
Fine.
不过猎枪可不顶用
But a shotgun is not gonna work.
我们需要一部狙击步枪
We need a sniper rifle.
做孢子丝菌病和脑膜炎球菌血症的DNA分析
Start running DNA assays for sporotrichosis, meningococcemia,
还有其它你能想到的测试
and any other boggle-winning words you can think of.
你刚刚才说要加大激素的量
You just said you wanted to increase the steroids,
-现在就...  -我改变主意了
- and now you want to just... - I changed my mind.
-但是...  -按朴克说的做
- But...  - Do what Park says.
你确实没有枪
Well, you don't have a gun,
但你有我的太阳镜
but you do have my sunglasses,
我的网球拍  虽然我不知道你拿来干嘛
my tennis racket-- I can't imagine why--
用来杀老鼠的
Had to kill a mouse.
你的小破太阳镜没帮上什么忙
It was really hard with those stupid little sunglasses.
还有我的钱夹
And my money clip.
还夹着钱吗
Was there any money in it?
现在没有了
Not anymore.
我能去睡觉了吗
Can I go to bed now?
还是你想进行体穴搜查呢
Or do you want to do a cavity search?
走的时候记得锁门
Lock up on your way out.
这太荒谬了
This is ridiculous.
我们浪费在寻找这个不存在的感染上的时间
Every moment we waste looking for a phantom infection
本可以用来治疗他的
is time we could be treating him.
按错误的诊断治疗
For the wrong diagnosis.
如果是自身免疫疾病  他就应该癫痫发作了
If it was gad, he'd be having seizures.
如果是感染
If it was infection,
在他的血液或者中枢神经系统中也会有迹象的
there would be some sign of it in his blood or CNS.
-而现在并没有  -只是暂时没有
- Which there isn't. - Yet.
我现在悔不当初听从豪斯的意见
I'm beginning to think we should just go with House's idea.
这就是豪斯的意见  他说...
This was House's idea. He said--
不  我说的是果冻
No, I'm talking about the Jell-O.
至少还赏心悦目
At least it wouldn't be so annoying to watch.
陶博  你有时间吗
Taub, you got a minute?
你真是个混蛋  你知道吗
You're an ass. You know that?
怎么了
What's the problem?
有些可爱的小护士给你烤饼干了吗
Some cute young nurse baked you cookies?
不  我差点被人捉奸在他家客厅
No, some guy almost caught me making out with his wife
跟他老婆亲热
in their living room.
这为什么会是我的错呢
And how exactly is that my fault?
如果不是因为你闹得我
If you hadn't been screwing with me
有了这个想法...
and put the idea in my head...
这么说我要是不让你有这个想法你还不约会了
So you don't date anyone unless I put the idea in your head.
你真该看心理医生了
You really do need psychiatric help.
与你不同
Unlike you,
我不喜欢戏剧化的生活
I don't need drama.
我喜欢我的工作
I like my job,
对生活也很满意
and I'm happy with my life.
你对生活还真满意啊
You're so happy with your life
以至于你没有比半夜回来吼我
you've got nothing better to do at midnight
更好的事可做了
than to come back into work to yell at me?
别插手我的生活
Stay out of my business.
你怪错人了
You're blaming the wrong guy.
对他有好处
Good for him.
已婚妇女虽然不能长久  但至少是个开始
Married one's not a keeper, but it's a start.
你真是个笨蛋
You're an idiot.
他有喘鸣音但是没有呼吸道阻塞
He has stridor but no obstruction.
他发生过敏反应了  给我气管切开包
He's anaphylaxing. Get me a trach kit.
手术刀
Scalpel.
没有用  没有呼吸声
It's not working. There's no breath sounds.
这没道理啊
It doesn't make any sense.
他的气道在切口以下的地方阻塞了
His trachea's blocked below the incision point.
-我们得试试消旋肾上腺素  -试过了
- We need racemic epinephrine. - We tried that already.
再试一下
We're gonna try again.
只有这个办法了
It's our only choice.
他能重新呼吸了  但很微弱
We got him breathing, but barely.
至少我们知道呼吸道水肿不是治疗引起的
At least we know tracheal edema isn't from anything we did
因为我们什么也没做
because we're not doing anything.
这是好事  因为自身免疫疾病
Which is a good thing, because neither gad
和全身性感染都不会引起过敏
nor systemic infection would cause anaphylaxis
或呼吸道水肿
or tracheal edema.
而过敏反应
And an allergic reaction
不会在入院三天后突然恶化
wouldn't get worse three days after he was admitted.
也就是说我们一无所获
So we've got nothing.
除非他还中着毒
Unless he was still being poisoned.
会是谁干的呢
By who?
在他出现幻觉的时候他老婆都不在这里
His wife wasn't even here when he hallucinated.
问得好
Good question.
现在我们成妄想狂了
Now we're the ones being paranoid.
鳞状细胞癌呢
What about squamous cell carcinoma?
如果只在他的上皮细胞
If it's only in his epithelium,
胸腔X光片上就看不到
it wouldn't show up in his chest x-ray.
有可能  但是...
It is possible, but...
不会导致幻觉
Wouldn't cause hallucinations.
如果同时有副肿瘤综合症就会
It could if you also have paraneoplastic syndrome.
去做活组织检查
Get a biopsy.
你觉得是癌症吗
You think it's cancer?
我觉得你该赶紧做活组织检查
I think you should get a biopsy.
承认吧
Admit it.
这是两小时前  我在你的衣柜里
Two hours ago, I found this in your closet
一只写着你名字的盒子里发现的
in a box with your name on it.
我知道你只有确定我不找了
I knew you'd move it somewhere outside your apartment
才会把枪放回屋子里
until you were certain I'd given up looking.
所以我得让你确信我放弃了
So I had to convince you that I'd given up looking.
那不是枪
That's not a gun.
是啊  是个镇纸  凑巧还带有
Yes, it's a paperweight with a handy
能存放45口径子弹的空间
storage compartment for .45-caliber bullets.
-那也不是真子弹  -承认吧
- And that's not a bullet. - Admit it.
承认我更聪明更狡猾吧
I'm more clever and more devious.
我甚至可以把它还给你
You can even have it back.
如果你因此再次入狱  也不是我的问题
It's not my problem if you go back to prison.
我是要让你承认
My problem is you thinking
你并不总是魔高一丈
you're always one step ahead of me.
它不是枪  所以什么也证明不了
This proves nothing because it's not a gun.
这是个道具
It's a prop.
从桃乐西·迪特里希魔术专卖买的
From Dorothy Dietrich's magic act.
看仔细了
Look it up.
她是唯一做接子弹表演的女魔术师
She's the only woman to ever do the "Catch a bullet" trick.
我是在一次扑克比赛里从她的道具师那里赢的
I won this off her prop master in a poker game.
-豪斯  -这是假枪
- House... - It's fake.
都塞住了
It's plugged.
你自己看
Look for yourself.
别拿那东西指着我
Hey, hey, don't point that thing at me.
一点儿都不危险  它又不是枪
It's not dangerous because it's not a gun.
豪斯  豪斯  别这样
House, House, just stop it.
好吧
Fine.
你这是做什么
What the hell are you doing?
-扣扳机  -别发疯了
- Pull the trigger. - Don't be insane.
子弹是空的
They're blanks.
你扣响扳机
You pull the trigger,
我假装吐点儿血沫
I drool a little fake blood,
然后吐出一枚子弹
and then I spit out the bullet that
骗观众是用牙齿接住的  来吧
the audience thinks I caught in my teeth. Go ahead.
开枪呀
Shoot me.
我不会向你开枪的
I'm not shooting you.
好  我来开枪打你
All right. I'll shoot you.
住手  豪斯  住手
Don't. House, don't.
就算是空弹  也会吓坏别人的
Even if they are blanks, people'll freak.
这不是真枪
It's not real.
所以你没能证明我有枪
Which means you didn't prove that I have a gun.
所以你什么都没证明
Which means you proved nothing.
承认吧
Admit it.
-好吧  -什么好吧
- All right. - All right, what?
你赢了
You win.
赢了的感觉真好
And it feels good.
你们错了
You were wrong.
别太难过
Don't feel too bad.
我们之前都错了
We all were.
他的气道没有水肿
His trachea wasn't swollen.
是被假膜堵塞的
It was blocked by a pseudomembrane growing across it.
说明他不是妄想症  只是个白痴
It means he's not paranoid, is an idiot,
而且确实中毒了
and was poisoned.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
给我一个纤维喉镜
Give me a machida scope.
抓住他的腿  他不会喜欢的
Hold his legs. He's not gonna like this.
因为你会不能呼吸
Because you're not gonna be able to breathe.
但我需要看看你的气道
But I need to see down your barrel.
好消息是  给你下毒的不是你妻子
The good news is the poison didn't come from your wife.
而是一种该死的小细菌
It came from a little bastard of a bacterium
它们的排泄物可以导致胸痛
whose crap can cause chest pain,
呼吸困难  皮肤溃疡
respiratory distress, skin ulcers,
令呼吸道产生假膜
the growth of pseudomembrane across the airway,
并且  在极少数情况下
and, in very rare cases,
产生幻觉
hallucinations.
打电话给疾控中心
Call the CDC.
说我们急需抗毒素
Tell them we need antitoxin as soon as possible.
白喉
Diphtheria?
我们没有想到
We didn't guess it
因为白喉几乎绝迹了
because nobody gets it.
你不该猛挖掩体
Instead of building bunkers,
而该去扎点激发剂
you should be getting boosters.
我指注射常规疫苗  防范那些真正可怕的东西
As in routine vaccines against stuff that is actually scary.
威尔斯医生请到康复科
Dr. Wills to recovery.
是白喉
Diphtheria.
豪斯完全凭空断定的
House pulled it out of nowhere.
厉害
Cool.
你是刚过来吗
You just getting in?
刚散会  关于新的停车验证系统
Had a meeting about a new parking validation system.
牛逼
Cool.
你感觉怎么样
How are you feeling?
不是太好
Not great.
但比之前好多了
But better.
抗毒素在发挥作用
The antitoxin is working.
他几天之后就可以回家了
He'll be able to go home in a few days.
这是好消息
That's good news.
我和孩子搬出去了
But we've moved out.
别这样  亲爱的
Oh, come on, honey.
对不起我骗了你  可是...
I'm sorry I lied, but...
我知道
I know, okay.
你是为我们好  可是我不在乎
It was for our own good, but I don't care.
我不想被欺骗
I don't want to be lied to,
也不能过那样的日子
and I can't live like that.
我不能住在那个家里
I can't live in that home.
求你不要这样
Oh, please don't.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you too.
所以你也不要再住在那里了
Which is why you're not gonna live there either.
我不在乎是不是有一天真的会需要那些枪
I don't care if we might need them.
我只知道  我不能带着那样的担忧去生活
I just know that I can't live my life feeling like we do.
在恐惧中度过人生太不值得
It's not worth living in fear.
好
Okay.
对不起
I'm sorry.
谢谢
Thanks.
知道吗  我们有些人
You know, there's a bunch of us
下了班是要出去乐一乐的
going to happy hour after work.
我想吃玉米片
I'm craving nachos.
一起去吗
You interested?
谢了  可我还要好多工作要做
Thanks, but I got a lot of work I need to get done.
如果你改变主意
Sure. Well, if you change your mind,
我们就在鲁蒂小店
we'll be at Rudy's.
好
Okay.
什么时候下班去喝一杯怎么样
Would you like to get a drink sometime after work?
我们三个一起  还是只有你我
You mean all of us or just us?
我的意思是我们两个
I was thinking just the two of us.
是陶博撺掇你这么做的
Did Taub put you up to this?
不是  只是我最近一直寻思约你
No, it was just something I'd been thinking about.
然后我想  管它呢
And I figured, what the heck?
不如问一声
Might as well ask.
我觉得这样不太好
Yeah, well, it's probably not a good idea,
毕竟我们都是同事
you know, with us working together.
你以前不是和一个同事结过婚吗
Didn't you marry someone you used to work with?
没错  可是...
Yeah. But...
好吧  行啊
All right. Sure.
什么时候
When?
今晚行吗
Tonight?
好
Sure.
我改主意了
Changed my mind.
好
Okay.
你改主意了我很高兴
I'm glad you changed your mind.